<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/44</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>297</id>
    <revision>
      <id>569</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T12:56:09Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;Nim sie aus, krüm sie wenig thue sie in ein keffeli, pulfter saltz, wein, vnd ein rauff brot, vber ein grosseβ fewr ge so sie aufgangen sind, saltz darin, ein handvoll peter...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1913">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;Nim sie aus, krüm sie wenig thue sie in ein keffeli, pulfter saltz, wein, vnd ein rauff brot, vber ein grosseβ fewr ge so sie aufgangen sind, saltz darin, ein handvoll peterli, siedβ wol in einanderen, so sie willst halthaben, so shüt ein halb glaβ vol essig darin.

''Take them out, [clean] them a little, put them in a pot, pepper, salt, wine and a [hunk] of bread, place over a large fire until they open, add salt, a handful of parsley, simmer well together, if you wish to preserve them, add half a glass of vinegar.''

===== 83.	Zuder gattung gsotner Fornen – On the types of boiled [trout] =====
Die fornen gleich förmig gesotten, früsheen ancken vnd lapriβ darin

''Boil the [trout] in the same way, add fresh butter and [liquorice]''

===== 84.	Gebratne Fornen – Fried [trout] =====
Die fish ausgenomen vnd gehicket, saltz vnd pulfter darin, salbinen bleter darin gelegt, auf dem rost wol gebraten, machein sossen von Angois, früshen ancken, pulfter, saltz, 2 löffel voll nidlen, essig, vnd wenig gehackten peterlin, in einer blaten auf der gluet alleβ lassen kochen.
Ein balchen oder ein brachslen gleichförmig wie die ge bratne fornen, gnug lapriβ vnd Angois daran.

''Take the fish and [filet it], add salt and pepper, lay in sage leaves, put on the hob and fry well, make a sauce out of Angois, fresh butter, pepper, salt, 2 spoons of cream, vinegar and a little chopped parsley, put in a pot and allow all to cook well.  For balchen or bream (?), do the same as for the [trout], add [liquorice] and [Angois] accordingly.''

===== 85.	Gesotten Gvundelen. – Boiled [Gvundelen/Grimdelen/Grundelen] =====
Ein guteβ glaβ voll wein siede, vnd shüte ihn heis in ein becki vnd die gsottnen grundeln darin, wol zu deckt daβ sie nit [under script: ausen]

''Simmer a good glass of wine, and, when hot, pour into a basin and pour in the [grundeln], well covered so that they don’t''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>14j0dk67m7bwys18oy6vyrhvt8g8v4n</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
