<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/8</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>261</id>
    <revision>
      <id>528</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T08:30:45Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;'''[13.b]''' Klopft 4 eyer wol, 3 löffel voll mäl wol vndereinanderen geklopfet, 3 milch shüsseli voll milch, daβ ein zartt teigli gibt, gar wenig saltz, mache im düpffe...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1719">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;'''[13.b]''' Klopft 4 eyer wol, 3 löffel voll mäl wol vndereinanderen geklopfet, 3 milch shüsseli voll milch, daβ ein zartt teigli gibt, gar wenig saltz, mache im düpffe gsotnen ancken heis, shüt daβ teigli mit den eyern vndereinandren in den heisen ancken, glut darunder vnd darauf, shawe daβ eβ nit anbrenne.

''Beat 4 eggs well, beat in 3 spoons of flour well, 3 milk bowls of milk, to make a soft dough, very little salt, heat [boiled] butter in a pot, mix the dough together with the eggs into the hot butter, heat above and below, make sure it does not catch.''

===== 14.	Ausgehultes brot – Hollowed-out [stuffed] bread =====
Brosinen brot im ancken geröstet, dan eyer, nidlen, rosinli, bulffer vnd saltz wenig vndereinandren lassen dicken kochn alβ dan darmit daβ brot ausgefült, ein wenig in nideln oder milch lassen weichen, das es ein wenig kleckt, dan strübe ein wenig mäl darüber, bind es mit einem fadn zu samen, in auffe gebaisen vnd auf die gluet lassen stehn.

''Fry breadcrumbs in butter, then let eggs, cream, [breadcrumbs], pepper and salt cook together until thick as this will fill the bread, soak a little in cream or milk, so that it is a little [klekt], dust a little flour over this, tie it together with a string, cook in the oven and leave on the [heat].''

===== 15.	Von Fastenring – On a [fasting ring] =====
Weiche den fastenring wol in der nidlen, den ring im ancken gebachen, dan darauβ genomen, zucker darüber.

''Soften the [fastenring] well in cream, cook the ring in butter, then take out [of the butter] (and sprinkle) sugar on top.''

===== 16.	Andere gatung deβ gefültn broteβ – A different version of filled bread. =====

[below script: Nim gsotnen ]&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>jxyhk71lg90ufycruw4cu42q3dfie15</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
