<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/35</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>288</id>
    <revision>
      <id>560</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T12:24:13Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;gethan, wol vndereinanderen geruhrt supenbrüche musgat nuβ, frushen ancken, pulfer vnd saltz daran, den shnepffen in einer blatten auf die shniten gelegt.  [possible scribal...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2064">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;gethan, wol vndereinanderen geruhrt supenbrüche musgat nuβ, frushen ancken, pulfer vnd saltz daran, den shnepffen in einer blatten auf die shniten gelegt.

[possible scribal error – the next two lines do not appear to continue the same recipe, but are very similar to recipe 57] put, mix well together stock, nutmeg, fresh butter, pepper and salt added, place the snipe on a dish on top of the slices.

===== 64.	Von köstlichen vögeln alβ Verneyssen oder vhrenhanen vnd der gleichen köstliche vögel zu rüsten. – On delicious birds such as [vernyssen] or grouse and how to serve [?] the same delicious birds. =====
Daβ geflügel sauber gestrupfft vnd ausgenomen, die fecken, hälβ, köpf vnd stil nit gestupft, so du ein kost lich mal hast, kanst sie vergülden vnd in die blaten zu den anderen kostlich vögeln legen, mit saltz vnd pulffer daβ gflügel ausen vnd innen gestreugt, nim böseβ mit wein genetzteβ werch ingwunden in die heisse äshen ver graben, bis daβ das werckh ein wenig trocken ist, aus dem werch wider genomen, mit einem steckh wol gestickt, dan gebraten, so eβ halb gebraten freshen ancken darüber.

''Pluck and [gut] the birds clean, do not pluck the [feathers] (from the) neck, head and [tail], if you are preparing a special meal, you can [gild/brown off (in pan)] these and place them in the dish with the other delicious birds, sprinkle the birds with salt and pepper both inside and out; take [böseß] drenched in wine and wrap them up, and bury them in the ashes, until the material has dried a little, then take them out of the material, spear them well with a spear, then roast them, and when half cooked put fresh butter on them.''

===== 65.	Gebratne Enten – Roast duck =====
Laβ sie gar aus braten, daβ sie noch in saft seie, zu einer sossen, den safft mit zwen teller aus getruckt aus der enten, den safft in ein blaten, bomerantzen, wein, ein

''Cook it just enough, so it is still juicy; To make a sauce, press the juice from the duck using two plates, put the juices into a dish, add oranges, wine, a''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>r1g8lh02rpaldb9x2d24xn5upbklugl</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
