<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/37</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>290</id>
    <revision>
      <id>562</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T12:31:52Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;So gibt eβ ein sossen.  ''to make a sauce.''  ===== 68.	Gebratne Shweinlin – Roasted piglet ===== So eβ wol gebutzt vnd aus genomen ist, haw ein weis brot zu 3. stuckhen,...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1710">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;So gibt eβ ein sossen.

''to make a sauce.''

===== 68.	Gebratne Shweinlin – Roasted piglet =====
So eβ wol gebutzt vnd aus genomen ist, haw ein weis brot zu 3. stuckhen, pulffer vnd saltz in daβ shweinlin, nim zwei stückli von weisbrot, einβ vornen, vnd einβ hinden in daβ shweinli, freshen ancken darin gethan, vnd wol zu geheffet, so wirtβ gar gut werden, dan gebraten, so eβ blateren wirfft, wenig kalt wasser darüber gossen.

''When it is well cleaned and gutted, cut a white loaf into 3 pieces, pepper and salt on the piglet, take two pieces of white bread, one at the front and one at the back of the piglet, with fresh butter added in, then bound well together, then roasted, if that it [blateren wirfft], pour a little cold water on the top.''

===== 69.	Eingemacht Kalbfleish – Marinated Veal =====
Früshen ancken in ein öhrig düpfelin, shneid daβ rawe fleish zu shnitlein darin, nit zuuil, sonder wie ein lege, bulffer vnd saltz darin, verdampffeβ darin, vnd wol zu gedeckt, kein brüche daran, daβ kalbfeish gibt von ihm selbst ein sossen, so eβ verdrupfft, ein halbeβ glessli voll wein darin

''Put fresh butter in an [eared] pot, cut the raw meant into pieces and add, not too much but like a [lege], add butter and salt, steam it in this, cover it well, do not add stock, the veal makes its own sauce, when it [starts to cook], add half a glass of wine.''

===== 70.	Ein K[c]ashen zu Machen – To make a [K[c]ashen] =====

Nim brotneβ fleish rein gehackt, in einer blaten mit freshen ancken, pulffer, saltz, bomeranzten oder die rinden wenig

''Taken roasted meat cut into pieces, put into a pot with fresh butter, pepper salt, oranges or a little of the rind thereof,''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>nm25x3y1c3s6c0aqjabpfqfwnkamwbt</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
