<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/34</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>287</id>
    <revision>
      <id>559</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T12:20:37Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;===== 61.	Gebratene Ha[a]ssen [superscript correction: a]– Roasted rabbit ===== Spickh den haasen wol, dan gebraten, zu einer sossen nim pfeffer bulffer essig, wein, wenig n...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2060">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;===== 61.	Gebratene Ha[a]ssen [superscript correction: a]– Roasted rabbit =====
Spickh den haasen wol, dan gebraten, zu einer sossen nim pfeffer bulffer essig, wein, wenig nägelin pulffer vnd er einander in ein brat pfann gethan, den hasen damit wol geshütet, so er in der blatten ist, mach wider ein sossen daran.

''Spear the rabbit well, then roast it, for a sauce take ground pepper, vinegar, wine, ground cloves and mix together in a frying pan, baste the rabbit well with it, when it is in the dish, pour more sauce over it.''

===== 62.	Gebratne Küngelin - Roasted [Küngelin] =====
Beltze eβ aus, nim essig, pfeffer bulffer, streugeβ darüb er, vber nacht in keller gelassen, rein gestickt, vnd dan ge braten. ein kleiner sossen zu machen, supenbrüche wenig wein freshen ancken, pulffer vnd saltz wenig bomerantzen rinden vndereinanderan ein wenig lassen kochen daβ küngelin dan beshütet.

''[V/Beltze (Clean?)] it out, take vinegar, ground pepper, sprinkle it over, leave overnight in the cellar, spear it and then roast. To make a little sauce, stock, a little wine, fresh butter, pepper and salt, a little orange rind mixed together and allowed to cook together, then pour over the [küngelin].''

===== 63.	Shoffstotzen – Sheep [stotzen ?] =====
Klopffe den shoffstozen wol, im pulffer vnd saltz, mit vmbgetröltein grossen steckh wol gesticket, dan mit pulffer vnd saltz bestreugt, dan in einen lumpen, zwüshen zwei breten gelegt, ein shwereβ bloch darauf, daβ wol getruckt werde, 24 stund also lassen bleiben, den knoden hawe nit ab sonder bind hen an den stotzen, dan in ein haffen gelegt, wenig [below script: von einer]

''Beat the sheep’s [stozen] well, dust in pepper and salt, with a large stick which has been rolled [in pepper and salt?] spear it well, then sprinkle with pepper and salt, then place it in a cloth between two boards, put a heavy block on top, so it is well compressed, then leave for 24 hours, do not cut off the [knoden] but tie it to the [stozen], then place in a pot, a little [below script: of a]''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>ksk4krlzoqk8r764cbu0vm5lw9g4eya</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
