<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/39</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>292</id>
    <revision>
      <id>564</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T12:38:24Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;Fleish im freshen ancken, ein köllen voll supenbruche darüber, laβ die stucklein fleish darin kochen, so du sossen von brotiβ hast, auch darin, wenig shäpreteβ brot, pul...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1824">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;Fleish im freshen ancken, ein köllen voll supenbruche darüber, laβ die stucklein fleish darin kochen, so du sossen von brotiβ hast, auch darin, wenig shäpreteβ brot, pulffer, saltz, zitronen safft oder rindenm vnd alleβ mit einanderen sambt der wachtlen auf einer shoffrenten kochen lassen.

''Add meat in fresh butter, a [ladle] full of stock. Allow the meat pieces to cook in this, if you have bread sauce, add this, add some breadcrumbs, pepper, salt, lemon juice or [beef] and let this all cook together on the heat with the [quail].''

===== 73.	Kloblwürst – [Klobl (veal)] sausage =====
Neie ein kalben netze zu samen wie ein darm, kalb er läbern, ein gantze milcken vom kalb wenig kalber hertz nur wenig wenig läbern, etwan einer weltshn baum nuβ groβ kalbfeish, ein shön weis stückli speckh dis alleβ vndereinandern wolgehacket pulfter saltz drey oder 4 eyer darunder gerühet, vnd rosinli, vnd alleβ in daβ darmnetzi gethan, dan wol verbunden oder ver neyt, dan in anken nit zu heiβ gelegt, sonst versteigt sie, las sie wol darin köcherlen.

''Sew a calf’s net together like a gut, calf’s liver, a whole calf’s [sweetbread], a little calf’s heart and just a little liver, a piece of veal meat about the size of a [weltshn] [walnut], a nice white piece of [speck] and mix this all together with salt powder, three or 4 eggs and raisins, put this all in stomach netting, then bind it or sew it well, then put it in fresh butter which is not too hot, else it will [come apart], and let it cook well in this.''

===== 74.	Gansen würst zu Machen – to make goose sausage. =====
Die Ganβ butze vnd strupft sie sauber, daβ hungeweid darauβ, shneide die haut sauber darauon, die haut

''Clean the goose and pluck clean, take out the innards, cut the skin clean away, the skin on the neck''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>4di34wjoj9zc49sg1qirxxm55r8s1l0</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
