<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/22</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>275</id>
    <revision>
      <id>547</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T10:55:30Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;===== 41.	Sossen über ein gebrattenen welshen hanen – Sauce over a fried [welschen] hen. ===== Nim ein stücklin kochteβ fleish warm auβ dem haffen zwishen 2 hölzige zel...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1781">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;===== 41.	Sossen über ein gebrattenen welshen hanen – Sauce over a fried [welschen] hen. =====
Nim ein stücklin kochteβ fleish warm auβ dem haffen zwishen 2 hölzige zelleren daβ safft gar wol auβ getruckt, dan daβ safft in ein blatten gethan vnd frischen angken darin, pfeffer vnd imber pulffer vnd ein wenig essig vnd in die blatten gethan, daβ wol kochen dan shütes über den hanen.

''Take a piece of cooked meat fresh from the pot, press out the juices between 2 [wooden plates], put the juices in a bowl and add fresh butter, add pepper and ginger powder and a little vinegar to the bowl, cook this well and pour over the hen.''

===== 42.	A.) Ein welshen hanen a la dobe – A [welschen] chicken a la dobe =====
Mit grossen langen speck wie man daβ wild bradt spickt, spickt den hanen, dan nim breidte shnidly speckh pullffer vnd saltz, ein grossen zibellen vnd thues in ein haffen, thue daβ welsh huon darin , wasser daran, so es jung ist thue nu rein wenig, ist es alt, mer daran, ein ganze maβ wein vndt gantze specery nägelin imber würtzen ein guoten theil lauch peterly, klain hölm vndt rosmarin dan in ein haffen freshen angken, ein wenig pommeranzen vnd 2 sorbonen blat, so eβ halber gekochet ist

''With big long [spit] as you would [put] a [deer] on a [spit], put the chicken on the [spit], then take wide slices of [the spit roasted bird], butter and salt, a large onion and put it in a pot, then add the [welschen] chicken, add water, if it is young just add a little, if it is old, add more, add a whole measure of wine and whole clove spices, ginger root and a good amount of chives and parsley, [klain holm] and rosemary and then into a pot fresh butter, a little bitter orange and two bay leaves, when it is half cooked [text unfinished?]''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>tpis53s0p3og746n8v32ffmyv1ovt9e</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
