<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/10</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>263</id>
    <revision>
      <id>592</id>
      <parentid>530</parentid>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T14:11:46Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1793">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;dan mit dem glas abgestochen, dan shön aufgerichten in ein blaten zwei gegen anderen aufgestelt, dan shöne ziger körbli [smudge] rund vmb gelegt, zucker vnd nidlen in die blaten geshütet, dan mit blümlin vmbstecht.

''then cut out (the foam) with the glass], then present it nicely on a plate, then put [ziger] baskets nicely around, pour sugar and cream in the plate, then place flowers all around.''

===== 19.	Geshwellte Mangeldkernen – Swollen Almonds =====
Ab disen kernen ziehe die haut daruon, dan bach sie in ancken wol, in ein thueg gethan, den smutz sauber ab gewüsht, dan im mörsel mit in körnli äniβ darund er gestosen, alleβ in blatn gethan, vnd zucker darunder, mit silberigen löffel gessen, daβ macht also ein gueten ap petite.

''Take the skins from these (almond) cores, then cook well in butter, put in a cloth, wipe off the dirt, then chop up with aniseed mixed in, put it all on a dish and sugar mixed through, eat with a silver spoon, this gives a good appetite.''

===== 20.	Rund geshnitne zitronen. – Lemons cut into rounds =====
Die zitronen breit gesniten, zucker darüber geshaben vnd ein wenig roswasser.

''Cut the lemons into thick slices, put sugar on them and a little rosewater.''

===== 21.	Von Restlen. – On [Restlen] =====
Shneid das gtisser daruon, gar wenig wein, die uestlen sollen zuuor im heissen ancken gewarssen werden, zimet, wenig äniβ vnd zucker, diβ alleβ im heissen ancken vnder ein ander gewarmet, so du wilst anrichten wenig roswasser darüber gestreugt. [below script: äpffel zu]

''Cut away the [skin], a very little wine, the [uestlen] should first be [cooked]in hot butter, cinnamon, a little aniseed and sugar, warm together in hot butter, when you wish to serve sprinkle with rosewater. [below script: apples to]''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>ql605t5uxms94b74ajxj6m70k84dxsk</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
