<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/52</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>305</id>
    <revision>
      <id>580</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T13:34:09Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;===== 105.	Wild bräth. – Roast [venison] ===== Daβ wildpräth muβ zuuor 2 tag wol ein gebeitzt sein nur mit saltz, noch 2 tagen thueβ in ein züber, bulffer vnd saltz wo...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1637">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;===== 105.	Wild bräth. – Roast [venison] =====
Daβ wildpräth muβ zuuor 2 tag wol ein gebeitzt sein nur mit saltz, noch 2 tagen thueβ in ein züber, bulffer vnd saltz wol darin geriben, 2 stückli reckhold erhültzli darin gelegt, ein handvoll reckholderberin wenig getruckt, essig vnd wein daruber biβ eβ genu gist, ein grossen stein darin gelegt, daβ eβ vnderen trucke mit einen deckle wol zu gedeckt, vnd alzeit vber den driten tag vmbgekehrt.

''The wild game must be well cured in salt 2 days before, then for 2 days put it in a tub rubbed with pepper and salt, add two small pieces of [elder wood], a handful of elderberries, slightly pressed, vinegar and wine poured over until there is enough, place a large stone on top so that it is pressed down, seal well with a lid, then turn regularly for three days (alternative: turn on the third day).''

===== 106.	Gebraten Zungen – Fried tongue =====
In der supen gekochet, dan mit kleinen oder grossen pfeckh, dan wol gebraten, ein sossen mit roten wein, rosinli wein beeri, zimmet vnd zucker darüber gemacht, vnd geshütet.

''Cook in soup, then with a little or a lot of speck, then fry well, and make a sauce of red wine, grape raisins, cinnamon and sugar sprinkled in, and pour (over the tongue).''

===== 107.	Shwinige Ripi – Pork Ribs =====
Brate eβ, dan 3 oder 4 reckholderbeeri gestossen, brot bulffer vnd saltz vndereinander darüber gesteugt, laβ eβ nit zu fast braten, ziehe eβ ab vor ein and [under script: eren]

''Fry it, then 3 or 4 elderberries crushed, bread powder and salt sprinkled over, do not let it fry too hard, pull them from each other,''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>2wg1sajy30962vpzbt55qqziu5gppvj</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
