<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/50</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>303</id>
    <revision>
      <id>578</id>
      <parentid>577</parentid>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T13:27:07Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1854">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;geshütet, las nit verkochen dan thue sie aus den thuech in ein blaten iedeβ besonder, darüber pulffer vnd saltz gestreugt so bleibtβ shön weiβ. So du eβ wilst frigass iert, so nim die mitleste bleter von mangold, sauber ge washen vnd gebrüchet, nim dan daβ knöβ, hawβ zu stücklen in ein häfflin, imber vnd pulffer darin, 2 oder 3 löffel voll gute milch oder nideln, laβ auf einer gluet ohne saltz kochen biβ du wilst anrichten.

''do not allow to boil, then remove from the cloth and place in a bowl, and sprinkle with salt and pepper, so it will remain nice and white. If you wish to have it fricasseed, so take the middle leaves of chard, wash them clean and [gebrüchet], then take the [knöβ] and cut into small pieces, add ginger and pepper, 2 or 3 spoons of good milk or cream, allow to cook on the fire without salt until you wish to serve it.''

===== 101.	Auff den tish ein groβ stuckh rind fleish oder ein huon auff zustellen –To present a large cut of beef or a chicken on the table =====
Wan eβ halber getsoten ist, wider ausgezogen, im früshen wasser sauber abgewäshen, vnd legeβ wider in die suopen daβ eβ shön weiβ bleibe, dan so du anrichten wilst, hawe die obere haut daruon legeβ auf ein seiten vff daβ fleish, vnd 2 kleine hickh thue darin, saltz vnd gehackten peterlin darüber gestreugt,

''When it is half boiled, take it out again, wash off in clean water, and put it in the soup again so that it stays nice and white, then when you wish to serve it, take off the top skin and lay it on the side of the meat, and make two small [cuts] in it, sprinkle over salt and chopped parsley.''

===== 102.	Sossen an ein gesottneβ huon. – Sauce for a boiled chicken. =====
Meerrätich im mörsel gestossen, dan ausgetruckt in ein [under script: blaten]

''Cut horseradish into pieces, then press out into a''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>lcxysfb7l74e0aa8plu3vv0mx2hazlu</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
