<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/38</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>291</id>
    <revision>
      <id>563</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T12:35:13Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;Daruon auf der shoffreten laβ kochen.  ''and allow to cook on the stove.''  ===== 71.	S/Fur gasset zu machen – To make [sur gasset] ===== Aus kalbeβ oder sonst brotneβ ma...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1591">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;Daruon auf der shoffreten laβ kochen.

''and allow to cook on the stove.''

===== 71.	S/Fur gasset zu machen – To make [sur gasset] =====
Aus kalbeβ oder sonst brotneβ mach breite shnitle ein gantze zibelen etwan mit 3 nägelin besteckt vnd die shnitli darin gelegt. Pulffer saltz freshen ancken, das gelb von einen ey vnd wein darunder geklopffet dan daru ber geshütet.

''From veal or other roasted meat cut broad strips, add a whole onion studded with about three cloves and the strips of meat. Add pepper, salt and fresh butter, the yolk of an egg and wine beaten together and poured over it.''

===== 72.	S/Fur gasset von ohren füssen shnürren der shweinen zu Machen – To make a sour [gasset] from pigs’ ears, trotters and snouts. =====
Die stuckh sauber gewäshn in einen haffen lind gekocht in einem gshirn von allen vnrath gesaübert, die füeβ ohren, shnurren gehalbiert, auf den rost gelegt, ein hand voll gehackt peterlin shäpret brot, bulffer vnd saltz, diβ alleβ auf dem rost darüber gestreugt, runden zibeln shiblicht gehawn in ancken geröstet, dise stuck darin geworffen, wol in der pfann auf geworffen, daβ gäl von einem ey in guten löffel voll suren senf vnd essig wol vnd [below script: einand]

''Wash the pieces clean, and cook until tender in a pot, then in a dish remove all unclean bits, halve the feet, ears and snout and laid on the grill; add a handful of chopped parsley, breadcrumbs, pepper and salt sprinkled over; slice onions and fry off in butter, then add the meat into the pan, add an egg yolk, a spoonful of sour mustard and vinegar.''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>otl4nkrp2lcq78hry9eacqwg487nv81</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
