<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/48</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>301</id>
    <revision>
      <id>575</id>
      <parentid>573</parentid>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T13:17:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2104">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;anken darin, wenig essig ein löffel voll lapriβ, diβ alleβ laβ auf einem glut kocherlen wol zu gedeckt.

''butter, a little vinegar and a spoonful of [liquorice], and cook on the fire well covered.''

===== 96.	Von Kalbβknochen – On Calf Bones =====
Im tüpffli mit heissen ancken verdrmpff ihn wol mit wein vnd specerry, darin wenig saffert, vnd ein lorbonen blat, so ist wol eingekochet ist, nim dan daβ gelb von 2 eyeren peter lin rein gehacket, wenig musgatnuβ darin, alleβ wol vnder einanderen geklopffet, dan darüber geshütet.

''Steam it well in a pot with hot butter and wine and speck, add a little saffron and a bay leaf until well combined, then add the yolk of two eggs and parsley, a little nutmeg, beat all together well, then pour over the birds.''

===== 97.	Schoff füessli – Sheep‘s feet =====
So sie wol gekochet sind, im häfflin mit heissen anken breit shiblechten zibeln wol geröstet, die füessli darin, pulffer saltz ein wenig essig supenbrüehe frushen anken darin das gelb von ein oder 2 eyeren, oder nach dem vil füessli saft, vnd wenig wein vnder die eyer wol geklop ffet, wenig gäl pulffer daβ ein gäle sossen gibt dan richts an.

''To cook them well, put hot butter in a pot (and add) [thick slices] of onion (until) well fried, add the feet, pepper, salt, a little vinegar, stock, fresh butter, the yolk of one or 2 eggs, even some of the juices from more feet, and a little wine beaten with the eggs, a little [gäl] powder so that a [gäl] sauce is made, then serve.''

===== 98.	Von gefülten gebratnen kalbβ brüsten – On roasted stuffed veal breast =====
Mach ein sossen in einer tarter pfannen in die gshwölte morchen, ein stückli fleish auβ der supen, mit 2 telleren truck des [superscript: saft] darauβ vber die morchen in der tarten pfann
Kalber milcken rein gehacket, auch darin frushen ancken pul[below script: ffer]

''Make a sauce in a tart pan containing soaked [morchen], press the juices from a piece of meat from soup using two plates over the [m/worchen] in the pan, chop in some calf’s [sweetbread] and also fresh butter,''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>meoc00sa82ls847ej9vn1dt0x5jhce6</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
