<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/9</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>262</id>
    <revision>
      <id>591</id>
      <parentid>529</parentid>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T14:10:54Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1960">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;Nim gsotenen ancken, las ihn heis werden, röste ein guteβ blätli voll brosinen brot wol kröffelechtig darin, dan zucker, wen ig wein, vnd zimet darüber, daβ ausgefülte brot, darmit ausgefült, mit den fadn zu gebunden, auch geweicht in nidelen oder milch, vnd in ancken gebachen.

''Take boiled butter, heat it up, fry a good bowl of breadcrumbs until [crispy], then (add) sugar, a little wine, and sprinkle with cinnamon, fill the stuffed bread with this, having been softened in cream or milk, then cook in butter.''

===== 17.	Gefüllete äpffel durch die Rüebhächlen – Apples filled with [grated apple] =====
Hawe die äpffel auf vnd bshneide sie, dan gehächlet, dasein gute blaten voll gibt, dan bach sie im ancken, bis sie shön gälb wärden, dan thue sie in ein blatn, daran ein glas vol wein, zucker, zimet, rosinli, Roswasser, Koch alleβ vndereinandern, dan aufgestelt.

''Core the apples and cut them up, then [grate them], so that you have a good bowl full, then cook them in butter until they are nice and yellow, then put them in a bowl, add a glass of wine, sugar, cinnamon, raisins, rosewater, cook everything together, then serve.''

===== 18.	Meyen Mueβ – May [mousse] =====
Etwan 4 eyer klopffe wol, milch darin, mach ein shaum linden ziger daβ darauβ, gesheiden mit essig, so er gekocht ist mit einer shaum kellen ausgezogen, nim 3 oder 4 körbli voll ziger in ein blatn, dan früssn ancken dar under gerühret, daβ so weis wird alβ der shnie, dan zucker darin, bis süess gnueg ist, ein viereggig wald glaβ genomen, mit auf gezogen, mit den glaβ gemacht,

''Beat approx. 4 eggs well, add milk, make a soft [ziger] foam from these, separate it with vinegar, when it is cooked pull it out with a foam [kellen], take 3 or 4 baskets of [ziger] on a plate, then mix in fresh butter, so that it becomes white as snow, then add sugar, until it is sweet enough, take a four-cornered forest glass, [use it to shape the foam,''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>5q154iumafttlxpddqgaw8yd1rranon</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
