<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/4</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>257</id>
    <revision>
      <id>588</id>
      <parentid>524</parentid>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T14:04:12Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1730">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;===== 3.	Ein hashen von Eyeren – A [muddle] of eggs =====
Eyrn hart gessotten, nim daβ weiβ daruon, rein gehacket bulffer, saltz, Rosinli, und ein gulten shübel früshen ancken wol vndereinandren gerühret, las kochen, und daβ gäl mitn von einandern gehawen, und darein gesteckt.

''Hard boil some eggs, keep the white; chop pepper, salt, raisins (or: breadcrumbs), and a good knob of fresh butter and mix well together, let it cook, and take the yolk from the middle, and put [the mixture] in it.''

===== 4.	Gefülte Ameleten – filled omelettes =====
Aus 2 od. 3 eyern, mach 2 dünne amelaten, zucker, nidlen, eyer, [above script: prosinli], wenig zimmet, rühreβ wol vndereinandren, nim frushn ancken in pfännli die obige stuckh rühr eβ vnder einandern, bis eβ dickh wird, dan früshn ancken in blaten dan shüt die fülle aus den pfännli danauf vnd macheβ eben, die andere decke darüber, mit einer blatn zu ge decket, vnd las sie kochn.

''Make 2 thin omelettes from 2 or 3 eggs, sugar, cream, eggs, raisins (or: breadcrumbs), a little cinnamon, stir it together well, put fresh butter in the pan and mix the top of it under until it is thick, then (add) fresh butter in the pan, then pour out the contents and do this again [?], put the first on top of the second and cover with a dish and let this cook.''

===== 5.	Bachne Eyer – Baked Eggs =====
Mache gsotnen ancken heiβ im pfännli, shlag ein ey in ein ein köllen, ein wenig saltz darauf, vnd wenig mäl, laβ eβ shön bachen, auf solche weis kanst noch mer bachen, vnd [below script: in ein]

''Heat cooked butter in a pan, beat an egg in a [pot], a little salt on top, and a little flour, let it cook well, you can cook more in the same way, and''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>4ljlojltwlbq1uer1izyz77wfohfe1x</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
