<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/45</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>298</id>
    <revision>
      <id>570</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T13:00:19Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;Ausen springen, so sie todt sind, shüte sie gleich in das kefeli bulfter vnd saltz darin, lass nit länger sieden alβ ein ty sieden mag, ein shubel frushen ancken darin, la...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1757">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;Ausen springen, so sie todt sind, shüte sie gleich in das kefeli bulfter vnd saltz darin, lass nit länger sieden alβ ein ty sieden mag, ein shubel frushen ancken darin, laβ ein kochen vnd richt an.

''jump out. When they are dead, pour them straight into the pot, add pepper and salt, and do not simmer for longer than a [ty], add a knob of fresh butter, allow it to melt and then serve.''

===== 86.	Früshen – Fresh (fish) =====
Die fish in gälen sossen gesoten, bulffer, saltz, wenig saff ret, gnug wein, wenig wasser, ein guten shübel früshen ancken vnd las ineinander sieden, ein mäl shweitzelin daran, alβ dan angerichtet

''Boil the fish in [gäl] sauce, (add) pepper, salt and a little saffron, enough wine, a little water, a good know of fresh butter and let this simmer together, add a roux, then serve.''

===== 87.	Von den Fishen Egli genant – On the fish called perch =====
Gihwell sie in wein vnd saltz, die auf ein teller gelegt, die haut abgezogen, in ein blaten, wie an ein hecht weise sossen gemacht.

''Cook [?] in wine and salt, lay on a plate, take off the skin, put in a bowl and make white sauce as for pike.''

===== 88.	Vngesaltzen Salmen – Unsalted Salmon =====
Nim ein handuoll peterli gnug pulffer, saltz darin ein halbeβ glaβ voll essig, ein guten shübel frushen ancken wein, pulffer vnd saltz vnd laβ also wol ein kochen.

''Take a handful of parsley, add enough pepper, salt and half a glass of vinegar, a good knob of fresh butter, wine and salt and let everything cook together well.''

===== 89.	Von gesaltznen Salmen – On salted salmon =====
Leg sie in wasser, dan shwell sie, essig, öl daran, vnd peterli darauf glegt.

''Lay in water, then swell them, add vinegar and oil, and lay parsley on top.''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>m9tar8q20gn4gwh45on1361rbvcbadx</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
