<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/54</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>307</id>
    <revision>
      <id>582</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T13:43:15Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;Die Wachteln wol gebutzt, die köpff vngestrupfft mit papyr umgebunden, kropffli vnd eingeweid ausge nomen, mit shnitlen speckh vnd räblaub eingewund vnd also gebraten.  ''Cl...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1476">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;Die Wachteln wol gebutzt, die köpff vngestrupfft mit papyr umgebunden, kropffli vnd eingeweid ausge nomen, mit shnitlen speckh vnd räblaub eingewund vnd also gebraten.

''Clean the quail well, bind paper around the heads without plucking them, remove crop and innards, wrap with cuts of speck and [vine leaves] and roast.''

===== 111.	Suessen haasen sossen. – Sweet rabbit sauce =====
Nim roten wein zimet zucker vnd wenig pfeffer darin las wenig vndereinanderen kochen, shüt dan vber den hasen

''Take red wine, cinnamon, sugar and a little pepper added, allow to cook together, then pour over the rabbit.''

===== 112.	Gebratener kalber läberen – Fried calves liver =====
Wol mit grossen steckh gestickt durch vnd durch in ein friβ kalber oder shaffnetzli eingewunden, dan die läberen am spiβ gebraten, dan ein sossen dar an gemacht mit zimet, zucker vnd roten wein, vnd laβ auf den shoffeten kochen.

''Pierce thoroughly with a spear and wrap in a fresh calf’s or sheep’s stomach, then roast the liver on the spit, then make a sauce for it with cinnamon, sugar, red wine, and allow to cook on the stove.''

===== 113.	Griliarden von wachtlen so vber gebliben – Grill of left-over quail =====
Shneid sie entzwei auf dem rost wol gebraten, laβ kein raug darzu komen, vnd braten 2 shnitli raweβ [below script: fleish]

''Cut in two, and then cook [the quails] well on the fire, do not allow to come into contact with smoke, and fry two cuts of raw meat,''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>4k9yvfxns2vthu4qxbmnzppohf85lr8</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
