<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/42</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>295</id>
    <revision>
      <id>567</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T12:47:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;dan früshen anken in blaten, 2 löffel voll nideln darunder, so gibt ein dicke sossen, gar wenig [above script: essig] wenig musgatnuβ. Dan hecht aus der blaten in die weise...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2032">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;dan früshen anken in blaten, 2 löffel voll nideln darunder, so gibt ein dicke sossen, gar wenig [above script: essig] wenig musgatnuβ. Dan hecht aus der blaten in die weise sossen gelegt, daβ thüchlin wider vom kopfli vnd den fish auf der shoffreten lassn koch doch nit zu lang, las ihn kochn daβ die sossen nit sheiden.

''then add fresh butter to the pot, 2 spoons of cream, so that a thick sauce is made, a little vinegar, a little nutmeg. Then take the pike from the pot and lay it in the white sauce, take the cloth off the head and let the fish cook on the oven but not too long, so that the sauce does not spilt.''

===== 79.	 Von Gebachnen Hechten – On baked pike =====
Den geshürpten fish ausgenomen, gesaltzen vnd im mäl vmb getrölt vnd wol gebachen, ein sossen daran, mit roten wein, zucker, zimmet rosinli in einen pfännlin vnder einander gekochet, den hecht darauf in blaten.

''Take the cleaned pike, salt it and roll it in flour and bake well, add a sauce, with red wine, sugar, cinnamon (and) raisins cooked together in a small frying pan, place the pike on this sauce on a plate.''

===== 80.	Von bratnen – On a fried (fish) =====
Den fish shiepe wol vnd die ohren daraus gehawen, daβ eingweid aus gehawen daβ vnsauber vnd die gallen daruon daβ eingweid in dupffli mit einer sossen wie man sonst zu andren fishen ein sossen macht, fer gekochet, früshen anken darin, so eβ wol gekochet, richtβ an, dan früshen anken pulfter vnd saltz in ein blaten, t/fhe du den fish auf den rost leght, hicke ihn zuuor 3 oder 4 bletli salbinen darin, dan weltze den fish [below script: in frushen]

''Scale the fish well and cut out the ears, cut out the entrails and remove the unclean bits and the bile [then] put the entrails in a little pot with a sauce as you would make for other fish, cooked on the fire, add fresh butter, when it is well cooked, serve it, then fresh butter, pepper and salt in a bowl, then you put the fish on the grill, before doing so add 3 or 4 [sage] leaves, then braise the fish''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>782t4r008fculc24idpa6ekfii9f5jp</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
