<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Page:Ms38990 Swiss recipe book.djvu/51</title>
    <ns>250</ns>
    <id>304</id>
    <revision>
      <id>579</id>
      <timestamp>2016-10-21T13:30:27Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Not proofread */ Created page with &quot;blaten, freshen ancken, pulffer, saltz, vnd wenig shäp eret brot, leg daβ huon in die blaten, vnd las vnderein anderen darin sieden.  ''pot, add fresh butter, pepper, salt,...&quot;</comment>
      <model>proofread-page</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1633">&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;pagequality level=&quot;1&quot; user=&quot;Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pagetext&quot;&gt;


&lt;/noinclude&gt;blaten, freshen ancken, pulffer, saltz, vnd wenig shäp eret brot, leg daβ huon in die blaten, vnd las vnderein anderen darin sieden.

''pot, add fresh butter, pepper, salt, a few bread crumbs, place the chicken in the pot and allow to simmer together.''

===== 103.	Frigasse von jungern hanen – Fricassee of young chicken =====
Butze sie sauber, shnide [superscript: sie] zu viertel, in der pfannen mir freshen anken wolgerüstet, ein hand voll rein gehacket peterlin, shnitlauch vnd shaloten, wol vnder einanderen gewarmet, vnd geröstet, daβ gäl von ein oder 2 eyern, 2 oder 3 löffel voll gute nideln vnderein anderen gerühret, dan die brüche vber den hanen in die pfannen, dan angerichtet.

''Clean it, cut it into quarters, put in the pan with fresh butter and roast well, a handful of fresh parsley, chives and shallots, fry together well, add the yolk of one or two eggs, 2 or 3 spoons of good cream mixed in, then pour the stock over the chicken in the pan, and serve.''

===== 104.	Andere gattung der Frigasse von jungen hanen. – A different recipe for fricassee of young chicken =====
Mach heissen anken im häffelin ein gute handvoll suren, salat, klein gekacket, lass ihn in ancken ein wenig kochen, dan wirf die hanen gantz darin, mach supen brüche, gäl pulffer vnd andereβ pulffer vndereinanderen mach mit gar grose sossen daran, freshen ancken vnd wenig wein

''Put fresh butter in a pan and a good handful of [suren], salad, cut up small, allow to cook in butter, then throw in the chicken whole, add stock, [gäl] powder and other powders, and make with a lot of sauce, fresh butter and a little wine.''&lt;noinclude&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>civ8gz6na5zr33vr3bi9amyo5oinuis</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
