<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Sympsons and Gregories Geometry</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>4631</id>
    <revision>
      <id>6962</id>
      <timestamp>2018-01-05T17:02:54Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ea22@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>39</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with &quot;Possibly: Elements of Plane Geometry. To which are added, An Essay on the Maxima and Minima of Geometrical Quantities, and a brief Treatise of regular Solids; also the Mensura...&quot;</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1017">Possibly: Elements of Plane Geometry. To which are added, An Essay on the Maxima and Minima of Geometrical Quantities, and a brief Treatise of regular Solids; also the Mensuration of both Superficies and Solids, together with the Construction of a large Variety of Geometrical Problems. By Thomas Simpson, Fellow of the Royal Society, and Professor of Geometry at the Royal Academy at Woolwich. (London : Printed for the Author; Samuel Farrer in Charter-House-Street; and John Turner at the Hand and Apple in Queen-street near Thames-Street, M.DCC.XLVII. [1747]) http://library.st-andrews.ac.uk/record=b2498891~S1
AND: A Treatise of Practical Geometry. In Three Parts. By the late Dr. David Gregory, Sometime Professor of Mathematicks in the University of Edinburgh, and afterwards Savilian Professor of Astronomy at Oxford. Translated from the Latin; with Additions. (Edinburgh : Printed by W. and T. Ruddimans, for Messrs. Hamilton and Balfour, M.DCC.XLV. [1745]) http://library.st-andrews.ac.uk/record=b2498894~S1</text>
      <sha1>03oqz2jzvo5unylmaclh5j81q6suwbn</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
