<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Hickes agst. Tindal</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>5670</id>
    <revision>
      <id>8486</id>
      <timestamp>2018-02-23T16:31:23Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ac101@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with &quot;Possibly:  	Two treatises, one of the Christian priesthood, the other of the dignity of the Episcopal Order. First written, and afterwards published to obviate the erroneous o...&quot;</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1121">Possibly:  	Two treatises, one of the Christian priesthood, the other of the dignity of the Episcopal Order. First written, and afterwards published to obviate the erroneous opinions, fallacious reasonings, and bold and false assertions, in a late book, entituled, The Rights of the Christian Church. With a large prefatory discourse in answer to the said book. All written by George Hickes, D. D. With and appendix; whereto are added in this edition several new tracts, viz. A particular treatise written by Isaac Casaubon of Geneva, entituled, De Libertate Ecclesiastica, of the liberty (or free estate) of the Church. Mr. Hughes's Preliminary Dissertations (to St. Chrysostom de Sacerdotio) wherein the authorityof the church, as it is distinguish'd from that of the state, is explain'd and defended, and all the objections of the Erastians answer'd, especially those of a late author, who has publish'd a book entituled, The Rights of the Christian Church, &amp;c. In two volumes. 3rd ed. (London : Printed by W. B. for Richard Sare, at Grays-Inn-Gate in Holborn, 1711). http://library.st-andrews.ac.uk/record=b2407849~S1</text>
      <sha1>etx0yz5csj204on6c430wmhdqnj1c3s</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
