<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en-gb">
  <page>
    <title>Danets Greek and Rom. Antiquities</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>5558</id>
    <revision>
      <id>8273</id>
      <timestamp>2018-02-12T14:21:46Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ea22@st-andrews.ac.uk</username>
        <id>39</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with &quot;Possibly: A complete dictionary of the Greek and Roman Antiquities; Explaining the Obscure places in Classic Authors, and Ancient Historians, Relating to the Religion, Mytholo...&quot;</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1013">Possibly: A complete dictionary of the Greek and Roman Antiquities; Explaining the Obscure places in Classic Authors, and Ancient Historians, Relating to the Religion, Mythology, History, Geography and Chronology of the Ancient Greeks and Romans; Their sacred and prophane Rites and Customs; Laws, Polity, Arts and Engines of war: Also an account of Their Navigations, Arts and Sciences, and The inventors of them; with the Lives and Opinions of their Philosophers. Compiled Originally in French, at the Command of the French King, for the Use of the Dauphin, the Dukes of Burgundy, Anjou and Berry: By Monsieur Danet. Made English, with the Addition of very Useful Mapps. [Pierre Danet] (London : printed for John Nicholson, at the King's-Arms, in Little-Britain; Tho. Newborough, at the Golden-Ball, in St. Paul’s Church-yard; and John Bullord: And sold by R. Parker, under the Royal-Exchange; and B. Tooke, at the Temple-Gate, in Fleet-street, MDCC. [1700]) http://library.st-andrews.ac.uk/record=b2449310~S1</text>
      <sha1>d6usw4ces4pig3l07crs1bf54wfikm1</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
